Leonardo David Manríquez Montoya

leo.david.mm@gmail.com · https://leonardo.wtf

About me

I'm a software engineer with ~10 years of experience. I started working when I was 18, and during this time, I've learned and grown in different ways, understanding what software engineering is and how I want to generate an impact in a company where I believe in its mission and vision. Something I love about my job, or my role as a software engineer, is solving problems and finding the best option to help people do their jobs.

I've worked with hybrid mobile apps, frontend, backend, and some architecture things (I love learning new stuff). I am a person who loves code, and every day, I try to be a better software engineer, improving my quality as a professional, taking care of details in things I'm building, creating good documentation, and working as a team.

A technical summary

- * I'm a native Spanish speaker, and I have a B1 English level.
- * I've used languages like python, go, php, typescript, dart, and javascript.
- * In a moment, I coded with Java and Kotlin for a native Android app, but I don't use it anymore
- * I've worked with backend frameworks like Django, Laravel, Express, NestJS.
- * I've used tools like Vue, Angular, TailwindCSS, and SCSS on the frontend side.
- * Also, I worked building hybrid mobile applications with Flutter and NativeScript.
- * I can model a database schema and work in general with Relational Databases, but I'm continuing to improve and learn more about them. Also, I worked with NoSQL databases like MongoDB and Redis.
- * I have docker knowledge for development flow and essential knowledge about Kubernetes.
- * I have experience deploying a multi-tenant/SAAS application in AWS.

Professional Experience

Uber

Software Engineer (Sept 2022 - Sept 2023)

Uber acquired Cornershop and aimed to move the operation into it. I joined an emerging team, where we built integrations between Retailer's API and Uber. Mainly, the integrations were about retailer's loyalty programs and their particular requirements. At Uber, I improved my English skills; I learned how to work in a big-scale company, the importance of Design Docs, monitoring, observability, and micro services.

Another of my responsibilities was to be part of the on-call rotations and take responsibility for unexpected situations.

Cornershop by Uber

Backend Engineer (Ago 2021 - Sept 2022)

I joined Cornershop in 2021. It was a beautiful moment because I dreamed of working in a company where, as a customer, I loved it. I worked in the merchant administration panel, creating reports and dashboards for our merchant customers. Here, I started to see how a big company works. I learned the importance of working with more people and teams. Also, I acquired more expertise in

writing tests, thinking in/coding software more scalable, communicating better, and improving my English skills.

CheckRocket

Software Engineer (May 2015 - Ago 2021)

Engineer behind checkrocket.com. I joined when this software was only an MVP, and my responsibility was to make the software more mature and professional. Since 2015, we've created a better piece of software using Laravel, driving into best practices like using CI/CD, testing, using migrations over the principal database, and upgrading the production environment to something more scalable on AWS.

I was like a Fullstack Engineer, coding from infrastructure, frontend, backend, and the hybrid mobile application.

Octano

Web Developer (Ago 2014 - Apr 2015)

I built sites for the agency's clients. Here, I started to have more experience working with customers, listening, and taking better requirements. I was beginning to see that my role is not only about code. It is about solving problems.

FXCM Chile

Web Developer (Mar 2014 - Ago 2014)

My principal responsibility was rebuilding the company's website to something more administrable and maintainable. I also helped send mailing campaigns daily with news in the forex world.

Open Latinoamerica

Junior Developer (Jun 2013 - Mar 2014)

I worked building custom tools for the agency's clients. I learned a bit about the educational environment using different LMS.

Netglobalis

Datacenter Operator/Junior Developer (Dic 2012 - Mar 2013)

This experience was an internship where I was the first line of support for clients in a technical call center and administrating some hosting servers. We had a pilot with an essential web tool connected to an Arduino, but it still needed to be finished.

Education

I started acquiring technical knowledge when I was 18. I studied in a technical school where I got a technical title in telecommunications. After that, from 2013 until 2017, I worked during the day and learned Computer Engineering at Duoc UC at night. Honestly, I don't feel that I learned a lot there. I acquired more knowledge and valuable tools working in different kinds of companies.

I completed some courses in Udemy about Flutter, GraphQL, and AWS CloudFormation.

Personal/Side Projects

Rocota (Present)

It isn't alive yet, but it's an ecommerce store for Rocota, a hand-made brand that creates beautiful pottery pieces. I'm building it with Shopify.

Tomaton (2020)

It's an application to enjoy with friends simulating a board game. It's a drinking game where players can play on their device, having fun in real-time with games like voting someone or timers. It was written with Flutter, using Cloud Firestore, and designed from scratch in Figma. It is abandoned, but I'm planning/developing a second version.

Pide Club (2019)

It was a small ecommerce store for people who needed control of their orders and products. The potential client was Instagram profiles that sell products or services via DM. Sadly, the MVP/pilot was not successful.

Motorex Chile (2015)

I built custom e-commerce over Laravel to solve particular business requirements in their B2B and B2C operations.

No tech things

I live with my partner, my little princess (my daughter), 2 bunnies, and 2 cockatiels. It's a beautiful family, even if it sometimes looks like a zoo. For some years, I volunteered in a pet rescue ONG; spending time helping animals was something meaningful, and I hope to help again in another organization. I love a good cup of coffee with a V60 Dripper and tasty beans. Sometimes, I play cards with friends, like Magic or Mitos y Leyendas, a Chilean card game. With my partner, we play Overcooked 2 a lot. We love that game.

Why could I be a good candidate for your organization? I'm not the most brilliant guy or the kind of person who could be the next novel, but I learn fast. I love this area. Building things, helping, or optimizing tasks is something meaningful for me. Are you continuing here? Thanks for reading and your time; see you